Poonam Rawat

Delhi, Delhi poonamrawat447_qcr@indeedemail.com 9315418572

Aspiring for job in a growth oriented organization where my recruiting experience and organization skills can be used for making a positive contribution in the human resource department by putting maximum efforts.

- Almost one years of experience as an HR Recruiter in IT and Non-IT recruitment.
- Hands on experience in using all web based technologies to market the Job Description.
- Taking the initial interview rounds and observing both facial expression and uttered words.
- Briefing the shortlisted candidates on key results areas so that they've a thorough understanding of the role and hence the possibility of later disagreements gets minimized too.
- Immensely experienced in convincing the shortlisted candidates on accepting the rolled out offer by throwing light on the non-salary benefits and good factors.

Work Experience

Approaching the supervisor

Human Resource Recruitment May 2019 to December 2019

Notify Visitors, Palam

21 May 2019 - 16 December 2019

- Attending the KRA briefing session conducted by the head of recruitment.
- Approaching the supervisor for clearing doubts.
- Sharing sourced resumes with senior members of the team & with the help of their suggestions, curtailing the list of resumes to the best ones.
- Sourcing profiles from leading portals like Naukri, Indeed, LinkedIn & Hirist etc.
- Shortlisted resume as per requirements.
- Taking their first round of interview and coordinating the selected one's written and technical round of interview.
- Personal attendance sheet maintenance of all employees.
- Communicate with different institute and recruitment firm regarding the openings and send them a suitable proposal.
- · Joining Formalities.
- · Other office activities.
- Reference and Background checks.

Human Resource Recruitment

HR Recruiter

Realtime Manpower Pvt. Ltd - Delhi, Delhi October 2018 to May 2019

- Screening resumes of the candidates based on the job description available.
- Short listing resumes based on several search factors such as skills, recently updated resume, location, experience, previous employment records etc.

- Calling the shortlisted candidates to know their interest about the job opening and take references from them.
- Convincing candidates to attend the interviews.
- Job posting on different job portals as per requirements of vendors or clients.
- Mass mailings as per requirements.
- Finalizing interview schedule and making the interviewer to be available for taking the interview.
- After interview sharing feedback with the candidates by mail or call.
- In case if they are selected then salary negotiation and follow up with them till on boarding.

Education

Master's in English literature

Kumaun university - Uttarakhand May 2016 to February 2018

Skills / IT Skills

RECRUITMENT, TALENT ACQUISITION, EXCEL, OUTLOOK, POWERPOINT

Additional Information

Key Skills -

- IT/Non-IT Recruitment
- Job Portals (Naukri, Shine, Times Job, Linkdln etc)
- Telephonic interview
- F2F interview
- Filtering CVs using keywords
- Composing job description
- Job Postings
- Briefing interview on KRA
- Follow Ups
- Mass Mailings
- Talent Acquisition
- Screening and Short listing
- Joining Formalities